<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>RackReaver</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on RackReaver</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 12:41:42 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 11:17:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>Email rackreaver@gmail.com
GitHub https://github.com/RackReaver
Twitter https://twitter.com/RackReaver</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 11:11:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>It all started when… I found myself inside the admissions office of New England Institute of Technology. My parents and the admissions officer both looked at me as I read through the program offerings. Reading one after the other something jumped out at me, I had never heard the term, “Cyber Security &amp;amp; Network Engineering”. The admissions officer noticed my curiosity and pulled out a class breakdown sheet, as I read each line my excitement grew, I knew this was my future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git for Document Management</title>
      <link>/posts/git-for-document-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 12:41:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/git-for-document-management/</guid>
      <description>The idea for this came to me while exploring and contributing to open source communities. It was (and still is) quite impressive how well these communities self govern using the Git version control system. Developers use the Git system to maintain a record of any changes to programming files and to me I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see why we couldn&amp;rsquo;t use the same system for documents.
The Markdown language One downside to using Git for document management is the need to use plain text files and the Markdown language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy, Quick and Seamless Incident Response Process</title>
      <link>/posts/easy-quick-and-seamless-incident-response-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 14:17:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/easy-quick-and-seamless-incident-response-process/</guid>
      <description>Incident response should be easy, quick and seamless. Anyone should have the ability to manage an incident with-in your organization with only a few minutes of training. I know sounds simple and well it is, the problem starts when we add decision makers to the equation. Everyone has ideas, experience and opinions about how incidents should be handled, but few have actually increased the productivity and efficiency of an incident response team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build a Simple Threat and Vulnerability Management Program</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-build-a-simple-threat-and-vulnerability-management-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 10:19:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-to-build-a-simple-threat-and-vulnerability-management-program/</guid>
      <description>Vulnerability management has been a key part of my career in information security. I have built two full programs at this point, one at a fortune 200 company and another at sub one thousand employee company. From the perspective of information security the process and program were nearly identical in how they were built, the differences only show in the remediation process.
Choosing a Vulnerability Management Platform This is an important (if not the most important) part of a security organizations toolbox.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
